{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "21st Century Literature",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "Elements of the Story",
    "LastModified": "15 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is the person or even non human creature in a work of fiction?",
      "answer": "Character/s",
      "choices": [
        "Protagonist",
        "Antagonist",
        "Character/s",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the characteristics of a person or any form?",
      "answer": "Character/s",
      "choices": [
        "Protagonist",
        "Antagonist",
        "Character/s",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main character of the story?",
      "answer": "Protagonist",
      "choices": [
        "Antagonist",
        "Protagonist",
        "Foil Character",
        "Dynamic Character"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What opposes the main character?",
      "answer": "Antagonist",
      "choices": [
        "Protagonist",
        "Foil Character",
        "Antagonist",
        "Flat Character"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the characters that normally do not undergo changes throughout the story?",
      "answer": "Static or flat characters",
      "choices": [
        "Dynamic characters",
        "Foil characters",
        "Static or flat characters",
        "Protagonist"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the characters that are capable of undergoing changes?",
      "answer": "Dynamic characters",
      "choices": [
        "Static or flat characters",
        "Dynamic characters",
        "Foil characters",
        "Antagonist"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What stands in contrast with another character, usually the main characters - to highlight the protagonist's personality and qualities?",
      "answer": "Foil characters",
      "choices": [
        "Static or flat characters",
        "Dynamic characters",
        "Foil characters",
        "Antagonist"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the location of the plot, including the region, geography, climate, neighborhood, and interiors?",
      "answer": "Setting",
      "choices": [
        "Plot",
        "Climax",
        "Setting",
        "Theme"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the organized pattern or sequence of events that make up a story?",
      "answer": "Plot",
      "choices": [
        "Setting",
        "Plot",
        "Theme",
        "Climax"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the literary element that describes the structure of a story?",
      "answer": "Plot",
      "choices": [
        "Setting",
        "Theme",
        "Climax",
        "Plot"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the introduction to a story?",
      "answer": "Exposition",
      "choices": [
        "Conflict",
        "Climax",
        "Exposition",
        "Resolution"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is essential to the plot because if there's no conflict there would be no plot?",
      "answer": "Conflict",
      "choices": [
        "Exposition",
        "Conflict",
        "Climax",
        "Ending"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the struggle between two or more opposing forces which is the center of the plot?",
      "answer": "Conflict",
      "choices": [
        "Exposition",
        "Climax",
        "Conflict",
        "Resolution"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the point in the narrative where tension, excitement, or stakes reach the highest point?",
      "answer": "Climax",
      "choices": [
        "Conflict",
        "Resolution",
        "Climax",
        "Exposition"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the part of the story's plot structure where the conflict is RESOLVED?",
      "answer": "Resolution",
      "choices": [
        "Climax",
        "Resolution",
        "Exposition",
        "Conflict"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to the main idea of a story it conveys to its readers?",
      "answer": "Theme",
      "choices": [
        "Moral of the story",
        "Plot",
        "Theme",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the message, lesson, or insight that a story wants to tell to the reader?",
      "answer": "Moral of the story",
      "choices": [
        "Theme",
        "Plot",
        "Moral of the story",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    }
  ]
}